# 今天咱主要是讲脆皮糊
Today let’s talk about the batter
# 你听 多脆啊
Listen, it’s so crispy
# 你按照比例做 就出不了大篓子
As long as you follow the formula, you can never make it wrong
# 我这个都给它做标准做量化了
I’ve already quantified the batter formula
# 低筋面粉250克
Low-gluten flour for 250g
# 泡打粉15克
Baking powder for 15g
# 油50克
Oil for 50g
# 水是380克 温水
Warm water for 380g
# 主要还是教大家怎么调脆皮糊
Those are the ingredients of the batter
# 生蚝搁葱姜搁黄酒稍微腌上
Marinate the oysters with scallion, ginger and huangjiu rice wine
# 它本身就有点咸鲜味
The oyster has some salty flavor itself
# 这就不用加盐了
so we don't need to add any salt
# 来点香油去腥
Then let’s add some sesame oil to get rid of the fishy flavor
# 胡椒粉撒点 给它腌上
A little pepper powder
# 够肥实
That’s very thick
# 咱把脆皮糊给它和了
Let’s mix the batter nice and well
# 和脆皮糊的时候先搁泡打粉 15克
Also, add 15g baking powder before mixing
# 温水 发酵比较快
Use warm water for the batter to ferment quicker
# 用筷子把泡打粉给它和开了
Use chopsticks to mix the baking powder well
# 加上面粉
Then add flour
# 加水
And water
# 我给你热上油 谢谢师父
I’ll prepare some hot oil for you. Thanks, master.
# 这是急脆浆的一种
This is actually one of the quick crispy batters.
# 传统的老脆浆就是 酵母点点儿碱
The more traditional batter has yeast and soda
# 油 50克
50g oil
# 半斤面粉 15克泡打粉
250g flour and 15g backing powder
# 50克油 380克的（温）水
50g oil and 380g warm water
# 这都量化了 标准化了
Those are all quantified ingredients
# 为了增加它的香味儿 香菜末儿
Let’s add some chopped cilantro for an extra flavoring
# 这就是跟传统的不一样了
That’s something different from traditional ways
# 稍微加点盐
A little salt
# 这个糊要给它发酵一下
The batter needs to ferment for a while
# 发酵个五六分钟十来分钟
Like 5-10 mins
# 这效果就会好
The fermentation will make it more crispy
# 这个糊和好了 一定要标准
Finally, we got the batter. It has to be standard.
# 你按照比例做 就出不了大娄子
As long as you follow the formula, there’s no way to make it wrong
# 少搁点黄酒
Add a little bit huangjiu rice wine
# 水开了 把生蚝焯一下水
The water boiled. Let’s parboil those oysters
# 稍微一焯水就关火
Just parboiling oysters a little bit
# 这生蚝把水给它吸进去
Make sure the oysters don’t soak up too much water
# 就是原材料的水分要吸干 不管炸什么
Make sure we get rid of the water for any ingredients before frying them in the oil
# 脆浆也饧的差不多了有五分钟了
The batter has rested for about 5 mins
# 饧完了以后这脆浆就别再搅了
There’s no need to stir the mixture again
# 因为一搅又上劲了
The stirring will add more gluten then create a tough texture
# 这会咱沾点淀粉
First, put oysters in the starch
# 锁住它的水分 不容易脱糊
To lock the water and get it coated tightly
# 专业叫不容易脱裤子
This is very important
# 跟炸鲜奶是一样的
The same as fried milk
# 五成油温 油温不能太高了
The oil temperature should be around 150 celsius. Don’t set it too high
# 定一下型就行 待会还得复炸
We need to settle the coat then re-fry it later
# 倍儿漂亮 金黄色
You see the beatiful golden color?
# 这时候脆皮糊就稍微加点水
Now we need to add some water into the batter
# 稀释点 薄薄的一层糊
To make it thinner, a thin batter
# 要不然太厚了不好看了
Or else the coat will be too thick and heavy
# 紫苏叶必须得炸 炸完了之后垫底
Perilla leaves also need to be fried then put on the bottom of the plate
# 一定要定一下型再翻
Make sure to settle the coat first then flip over
# 倍儿脆
So crispy
# 牡蛎回一下锅
Let re-fty the oysters one more time in a high temperature
# 油温最少是八成热
The oil temperature should be at least 250 celsius now
# 叫它把水分给它吐出去
To drain the water thoroughly
# 迅速的捞出来 出锅喽
Get them out of the oil quickly
# 里头油全打出去了 嘎嘣脆
Now they should be all nicely fried and super crispy
# 你听这声音 咔吧咔吧的 齐活
You can tell the crispiness from the chewing sound
# 师父您看 您听
Master, did you see this?
# 多脆啊
Wow that’s so crispy
# 听声音 嘎嘣脆
Listen to the crsipy sound
# 下手 大爷 您先尝
Da Ye, have a try!
# 瞧这酥脆的声音
Such a pleasant sound
# 这糊调的好
The batter is mixed really well
# 这是师父十多年前教的我
This is what my master taught me ten years ago
# 真好吃 这应该说是
Yummy! This is the paradigm of
# 糊好 原材料好 手艺好 传承好
Great ingredients, excellent cooking skills and continuous heritage.
# 师父是什么 是味精
Masters is sort of like MSG
# 因为过去有些原材料不是那么很好
Because back then, the quality of some ingredients was not that good
# 也不是很新鲜
or not that fresh
# 师父您尝尝这个菜行不行
"Master, please try to see whether this dish satisfy the standard"
# 一尝不够鲜
Master felt that the umami flavor was not strong enough
# 师父到味精罐儿里头捏点味精
Master pitched some MSG
# 往这菜里边一扔 行了
and added to the dishes. "Now is good"
# 所以师父是什么 师父是味精
So, Master is like MSG
# 这个例子可能有点不太恰当
This metaphor could be a little bit fuzzy but you know what I mean
# 但是有一样 师父就是调味
Master is seasoning
# 像你师父说的
That’s what your Master said
# 调味 调情 调水 调心
Season the flavor, the emotion, the water, and the heart
# 这很重要
That’s very important
# 所以今天刚强做这个
So the dish Gang Qiang (Chef Wei) did today
# 非常地道的脆皮炸生蚝
Very authentic crispty fried oysters
# 我再来一个啊 再来一个
I’ll just take one more!